WWW.MY-SUBS.CO
If anybody has an advantage or
an idol and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
Give me a minute.
So, I'm playing this for Owen.
- For Owen.
- Yep.
So, last night,
right before Tribal Council,
Cody hands me the idol back
because he trusts me.
And I feel like
a terrible person.
But I decided to blindside Cody
and I played his idol.
And then Karla thought,
"Oh, my god, something's afoot."
I will play mine.
And so she immediately
pulls out
- her idol and she plays it.
- Okay.
Incorrectly.
So, the plan went perfectly.
Both idols are out of the game.
But I still have an idol.
And Cody goes home.
Cody, the tribe has spoken.
You have made it
to the final five,
but this game is far from over.
Tonight you will be taken
to a new beach...
to start over.
- Oh, my God.
- This is the beginning
of the final push
to get to the end.
Oh, Jeffrey.
Dig in and hang on.
We're in the final stage.
We're on day 24.
I don't have that much in
the tank but I got to find more
because I think I've got
a strong chance of winning
if I can get to final three.
I'm the guy hiding in
plain sight. I am the assassin.
One by one,
my opponents are falling
and I'm continuing
to move forward.
No one is looking at me yet.
But there's no breaks
in season 43.
I've got to pull it together.
For me, making the final five--
it's almost hard to believe.
My game started so poorly.
Like, I've been
blindsided. I've been
left out of votes and I've
recovered.
But now I need to be perfect
heading into these
last few days in order to
reach the top.
All season, I've been playing
this sort of subtle game,
and so it was important
for me to take out Cody.
And it feels like,
"Man, I just made
this crazy move."
Like, almost-- Like, it feels
historic, almost.
Now it's like,
my threat level
is probably off the charts.
But I do have
another idol in my bag.
So, like, I know that I
can punch my ticket to final
four and nobody knows it.
It takes a lot
to get to the final five.
I've been on the right side
of every single vote.
I can say I made every
single move correctly
to get to this spot, and nobody
else can say the same thing.
But I wasn't able
to make any, like,
really huge,
flashy moves, and so
I need to push through
to the end
and fight for my case.
- This is the final five
of you, right here.
- Top five, baby.
- Final five.
- Five, baby.
You know it.
Day 24 Karla is struggling.
I don't have an idol.
I'm at the bottom.
Busted ankle,
stitches still in my finger.
Just goes to show that, like,
I have the heart of a warrior.
I'm still out here.
I'm not giving up.
I'm not gonna go out
without a fight.
That fight that's in me
I think is unmatched.
This is a free-for-all.
You have to cut anybody
who stands in your way.
I'm ready to step up. I'm gonna
have to scrap, claw and fight.
I'm gonna flip
a Metallica switch,
you know, go into metal mode.
People see me as a threat.
Hell yeah,
I want to be a threat.
We should have fuel.
We're exploring a new island.
Everybody's got bumps, bruises.
We're all depleted.
You know, we worked all season
to have built
your own little civilization.
And then
to have it all dismantled
at the 11th hour-- I mean,
part of me was surprised
and part of me's not
because that's the season
we're playing.
I don't have that much in the
tank, but I got to find more.
When you get deep in Survivor,
it's all about
living to the next day.
Whoa!
What is "whoa"?
More than mail!
Wh-- Oh, God.
- Oh, man.
We're going on a runabout.
As soon as we got back to camp,
I find five envelopes
in the tree mail,
one with each name on it,
says "clue to secret advantage."
So here we go again.
This note basically says
in order to get a clue
about where this
advantage is hidden,
you have to solve
this word scramble.
Everybody's trying to unscramble
faster than the other person,
and I do not want Karla
to find this advantage because
the game I need to play to win
includes getting Karla out.
Final advantage of the game.
We don't know what it is.
It could be,
like, an idol nullifier.
It could be
the Challenge Advantage.
We have no idea.
All we know
is it's an advantage.
And I'm nervous because
I don't think anybody wants
to take me to the end.
For me, it's really important
to try to get this because
I'm at the bottom.
I'm injured. Right? I'm gonna
need any advantage possible.
Starting to unscramble
the words, I am in my zone.
I've been doing my Wordle.
I'm feeling good.
So, I am dying
to get this advantage
before the biggest threats
in the game: Jesse and Karla.
I figure out the phrase.
And the note says:
So I start running.
Right as I'm figuring out
what it is,
Karla takes off,
and she is
the last person I want
getting this advantage.
Now it's a matter of finding
the advantage, right?
And, uh,
that's where
I'm a little disadvantaged
because of my busted ankle.
Part of the clue says
"lifeless." The only thing that
could be lifeless is a tree.
I get most of the words, except
I'm stuck on the word "prints."
Like, "footprints in the sand,"
and I realize it's "sprint."
So, once I get that
I take off like
a bat out of hell.
I'm limping down the beach
because of my busted ankle.
And then, "Pew!"
I see Owen just sprint past me.
If he finds it first I'm gonna
be so upset because I was able
to unscramble this thing,
and I'm like, "Gosh."
Owen is by the rocks.
And I'm like, "Great."
I think it's by the beach.
I'm like, "Let me
find a dead tree."
I'm desperate.
And then I remember
that the clue said
"knots"-- K-N-O-T--
"knots," and I realize
I am looking for a tree
with a rock at the base.
"I stand near the sea
with a rock at my surface.
Long since..."
What is that word?
It's killing me.
I'm looking,
I'm looking, I'm looking,
but there's nothing
in this tree.
There's a knot at my surface.
And then I see Owen
running back past me
the opposite way
towards another dead tree.
I start investigating trees
right along the ocean line,
and I see one.
And I'm like, "Let me
go check out that dead tree
and maybe I can
catch up the him."
I start looking by the root
where the rock is,
and I'm getting
to the knot in the tree,
and Karla
just gets right in there.
Aah!
I'm furious.
Karla scoots on in there
and yoinks that advantage
when it is two inches
from my fingertips.
Aw...
I am furious because not only
was I this close to getting
the advantage, the only person
that I did not want
to find the advantage
yoinked it out from under me.
The latest example
of Charlie brown
getting the football
yanked out from under him,
and me just kicking that air
and falling flat on my back.
Aah!
It sucks.
I feel like I am
the only one that needs
an advantage right now because
of the state that I'm in.
You know, I'm already beat up,
I'm beat down,
the only one on the outs.
And, of course,
this is what I need.
I was supposed to find this
advantage. It's kind of like
I was sent, like,
this message from up above
or from my wife,
saying, like, you can't give up.
Come on in.
Look at that five.
Like warriors
entering the coliseum
for a battle.
All right, shall we get
to today's immunity challenge?
- Yes, sir.
- First things first, Cassidy,
- Wah.
- take back the necklace again.
- Thank you.
- Yep.
Once again, immunity is
back up the grabs.
Let's get into
today's challenge.
Yes.
Before you do, though...
- Yes?
- Today we were
able to duke it out
for an advantage,
and, uh, I was able
to snag that advantage
this morning
for a final five challenge.
Nice job.
I'll take it.
- Okay. Thank you.
- Well done,
Karla, with a bad ankle.
All right, we'll
deal with this in a moment.
- First, I'll explain
the challenge.
- Okay. Cool.
For today's challenge,
you're gonna
maneuver a buoy
through a series of obstacles.
You'll then use two handles
to transport
puzzle blocks
over a hinged balance beam.
Once you have all your blocks,
you will use them
to solve a word phrase.
First person to finish
wins immunity.
Guaranteed a spot
in the final four,
where you can't be voted out.
You will either
win your way there,
you'll be taken there, or
you will fight for it with fire.
Huge stakes. In addition,
you are playing for reward.
Want to know
what you're playing for?
- It's a protein burst.
- GABLER and OWEN: Whoa.
The winner of this challenge
will be taken to the sanctuary
where you will enjoy steak,
- Oh...
- baked potatoes,
- Oh... my God.
- veggies, wine
and cheesecake. That is
the energy you need
for the boost
at the final four challenge.
Big stakes.
Losers, Tribal Council,
- Big stakes.
- where after 24 days,
somebody will be voted out
of this game, their dream
of winning Survivor 43
will fall a little short.
Karla, let's get to
your advantage. Today,
you will start with
ten of your puzzle blocks--
roughly a third--
already at your finish table.
- Okay.
- So, depending on
how many you take at once,
it can save you
one, two, or even three trips.
It's a decent advantage.
The question is
- what will you do with it?
- Okay.
We're gonna draw for spots
and we'll get started.
Day 24.
Here we go!
All right.
Here we go.
For immunity and reward.
Survivors ready?
- Go!
- ♪ ♪
The first step is you're
maneuvering a buoy
through a series of obstacles
and that buoy's gonna
have to go wherever
the rope goes.
Day 24. Everybody exhausted,
but you can feel the energy
knowing that
the end is in sight.
That million dollars--
you can almost reach it.
Owen off to a fast start.
Here comes Cassidy,
fresh on the heels
of an immunity win,
would love it again.
Gabler right behind,
then Karla, bad ankle at all.
Jesse struggling.
The only player yet to win
an individual immunity,
and it's not looking
promising right now.
Owen continues
to tear up this course.
Cassidy right on his heels.
Here comes Karla and Gabler.
Jesse's through
the first obstacle!
He's now swimming to catch up.
It's gonna be Owen
who gets out first.
Karla's made up more time,
but she's kind of knotted up.
Owen gonna be first
to the puzzle blocks.
You're good.
Start untying the bag.
Karla's here.
Here comes Cassidy.
She's gonna start
untying her bag.
Jesse's now through,
leaving Gabler
in dead last.
Owen whipping through his knot.
Owen has his puzzle blocks.
Dump 'em on the table.
Here comes Gabler.
Get 'em all out, Owen.
That's it.
Karla has her puzzle blocks.
There's Cassidy.
Once you have them untied,
start transporting
as many as you can at a time
using your two handles.
Karla gonna be first
out of the gate.
Karla made fast work.
Karla has the advantage
in this challenge.
Got to come back
and start again. Here goes Owen.
Getting across this beam
is not easy.
You can't use your body,
you can't go vertical.
Owen slips, he loses everything.
Here goes Karla.
Can she make that move--
the pivot?
Yes.
Karla already has
ten of her blocks at the finish.
Karla... nice job.
She is in the lead despite
being injured
in the last challenge.
Here comes Jessie,
here comes Gabler.
Here comes Owen and Cassidy.
Gabler's across
the first obstacle.
Owen now figuring it out.
That pass went very fast.
Gabler's good.
There's Owen,
there's Cassidy with blocks.
Here comes Jesse.
Everybody now starting
to get the rhythm,
but it is Karla
still in the lead.
Here comes Owen,
trying to close the gap
on Karla.
Owen has really
picked up the pace.
Gabler now starting
to get it, too.
Cassidy's in it.
Karla, with her last blocks.
This is it.
Karla can start
working on that puzzle.
It is Karla the first.
She now has a time advantage,
which is sometimes all you need
at the puzzle phase.
Owen's across.
Can he get up the steep steps?
He does.
Owen is good.
Here comes Jesse.
You're still in it.
It is a word scramble
you got to solve,
so this challenge is not over.
Here comes Cassidy
with more blocks.
Here comes Owen
with his last blocks.
Owen is there.
Owen can start working on it.
It is now Owen and Karla.
It is a word phrase.
Here comes Gabler
with his last blocks.
Gabler can now start
working on the word phrase.
There are lots of words that
you can form with these letters.
You need to form the right words
in the right order,
before everybody else.
Cassidy back with the last
of her blocks.
She's in on it. Here comes Jesse
with the last of his.
He's in on it.
Everybody now working on
the word scramble.
This challenge is on.
Final five.
You want a spot at four
because they can't take you out.
You will always have a shot
to earn your way to the end
through fire.
At the very least,
you will have some control
tonight at Tribal
because you are safe.
It gives you a little bit
more power in the game.
Lots of different words
being formed.
You're looking
for the right words.
"What is it? What's the phrase
I'm looking for
"that will guarantee me
a spot at final four?
"I want to be safe
tonight at Tribal.
24 days into this game.
I'm not going home tonight."
Lots of thinking
going on right now.
And then, suddenly,
it's gonna pop.
Somebody's gonna get one word
and that word's gonna
open the entire phrase.
Then it's a race
to finish before
somebody else figures it out.
That's how this will end
in a hurry.
Karla now making a move.
She thinks she's
on to something.
Question is, is she right?
Is she on to something?
Owen making a move now.
Karla moving more letters.
Karla feeling good
if she's right.
Owen taking
a different approach now,
trying a new word.
Sometimes that's what
you have to do.
You think you have a word,
you're not sure,
- replace it with another word.
- No.
No.
Like any good
word phrase on Survivor,
there are words
designed to fool you,
words designed
to make you really wonder,
"Is it this?
"It could be this.
"But I can't fill out
the other blanks.
Something's not right."
When you get it,
you will know it.
Owen making more moves again.
- Quickly moving letters.
- Let's go, Jeff!
Owen thinks he has it.
Say it.
"You cannot hide
in a dangerous game."
- And you won't have to.
Owen wins
- Let's go!
- individual immunity,
guaranteed a spot
- Oh, my God.
in the final four.
Oh...
You cannot
- be voted out
of this game anymore.
- Oh...
You will have a shot
at getting to the end
one way or another.
Huge challenge.
- Huge effort by everybody.
Big win.
- Owen, you...
Oh, my God.
- ♪
♪
- Great win, amigo.
Wow.
- Owen, come on over.
- Yes, sir.
- Well done again.
- Thank you, thank you.
- You know what this feels like.
- Oh, feels good, Jeff.
- You are safe,
cannot be voted out.
- Thank you.
Guaranteed a spot in four.
- In addition,
you've earned reward.
- Oh.
- Oh, God. Okay.
- So you have steak,
baked potato.
You're gonna choose one person.
- Oh.
- They're gonna go with you
to the sanctuary.
Who are you gonna bring
with you? And in doing so,
who are you gonna leave behind?
I got to take Cassidy.
- I'm sorry.
- Cassidy, come on over.
- Tears start.
- Thank you so much.
Three of you going back to camp.
Tribal Council tonight,
where, sadly, one of the four
of you-- Cassidy, Karla,
Jesse, Gabler-- your dream
of winning this game will end.
You two, head out.
Boat'll pick you up.
Enjoy your afternoon
at the sanctuary.
- Congrats.
- Thanks, Jeff.
- Nice work.
- Thanks, y'all.
- Great job, everyone.
- Head straight down
- to the water.
- Okay.
All right, Karla, Jesse, Gabler,
got nothing for you.
Grab your stuff up. Head back to
camp. See you tonight at Tribal.
Thanks, Jeff.
After watching Karla
snatch the advantage
from my fingertips,
I was feeling defeated.
But after winning,
it reminds me of my home,
New Orleans,
and the never-say-die attitude.
And I'm back on top.
It feels amazing.
Wow.
- Oh, my God. I see bread.
- Oh, my gosh!
I finally get
to experience the sanctuary.
Oh, my gosh. Jeff has
outdone himself this time.
My God. Look at that.
- The mushrooms.
- Oh, my gosh.
- Wait. Oh, my God.
Is this is real?
- Oh.
This is real.
Sitting at the table
with my dear friend Cassidy
with the immunity necklace
around my neck,
a glass of wine
and a big juicy steak,
I feel like a king.
- Okay.
- Cheers to you and your win.
I'm so proud of you.
Cheers. Thank you.
Just like you yesterday.
It feels
amazing to win
my third immunity necklace.
I'm gonna be so sick after this.
I don't care.
And now this reward
is about putting myself
in a position to win this game.
Me too.
Is that what we're thinking
tonight or are you thinking that
Jesse's kind of emerging
as a bigger threat?
- It's hard to say.
- I know.
Karla and Jesse--
they are absolutely threats.
Karla has proven
to be a very astute player.
She is a wizard with puzzles,
she is tough as nails,
and she is smart,
and she can talk.
So if she makes it to
the final three, she could win.
But on the other hand,
Jesse is dangerous. Jesse
was the mastermind behind
the biggest move of the season.
He's gonna get all the credit
in the eyes of the jury.
And I think if I'm sitting
at the final three
with Jesse, I lose.
I feel like
Jesse's the favorite,
right, after last night?
- Yeah.
- I think for a modern
Survivor jury,
they want to see the moves.
- And, like, after last night,
he's so threatening.
- Yup.
I feel like Owen
is leaning towards Jesse,
but my focus is Karla.
You know, she was trying
to come for me the other vote,
and I don't trust her at all.
So, I would like
to see Karla go tonight.
The problem with me is
I feel like
- I have driven a lot
of the votes, but...
- Mm-hmm.
...since I've done it
- with Karla... Yeah.
- With so many people? Yeah.
- She gets more of the credit.
- Mm-hmm.
And for some reason--
I don't know why-- I mean,
maybe it's her personality
that makes people
take her more seriously.
- So would your preference
be Karla?
- Yeah.
'Cause I don't want to sit
at the end next to her
and have to, like,
differentiate my game from her.
- Me, you and Gabler all have
pretty different games.
- Mm-hmm.
I don't really think Gabler has
too much of a shot right now.
I don't-I don't think so,
either. I love the guy, but...
- But...
- I don't think people would
take him seriously as a...
Yeah. So I think
I need that move.
I think you need it, and I think
she's more threatening
than Jesse in terms
of challenges and fire.
Yup. So are we feeling,
like, Karla tonight?
- That's how I feel. Do you...
- Yeah.
- You feel that way, too?
- Yeah, I think so.
Everybody who's come after me
and written my name down,
I've managed to blindside
and get out of the game.
And with Karla,
I think it would be a good move
for me to get her out
before she tries to get me out.
- All right.
All right, this will be my steak
and potato
and eggplant right here.
I am crushed, actually.
I was hoping that, uh,
Owen would pick me
today because
I just have
so little in the tank,
and it's such
an important time in the game.
And I feel like, you know,
mentally, I'm breaking down.
Gosh, we've been
absolutely starving out here.
I don't think
you can underestimate
how important it is
to have nourishment
at the eleventh hour.
Just got to pull it together
a little bit longer.
And I'm just hopeful that...
I can hold it together
another couple days.
It's gonna be between
me and you.
- Yeah.
- That's-that's the hard part.
I don't know
what the hell to do.
Cass. It...
We have to flip it on Cass.
That's literally the only way.
Is Owen gonna
go for that, though?
No, we have to get Gabler.
I have Jeanine's idol,
and nobody knows it,
so I'm gonna play it tonight
for myself so I'm safe.
But right now,
I'm just nervous.
I'm nervous about,
you know, the path forward.
- He's voted with you, right?
- He has.
The winner of
the final immunity challenge--
they get to choose who they
sit with in the final three,
and the other two have
to have a fire-making challenge.
Me and Karla
are being perceived as, like,
the top threats in this game.
So, if Karla gets taken out
and I make it final four
and I don't win immunity,
they would want me
to make fire, and
I don't want
to go out in fire.
Like, I don't want to go out.
I want to make it to the end.
I'm more scared
about tonight than last night.
You don't say.
I am pitching Cassidy to Jesse,
but in reality,
I want to put a target
on Jesse's back
because he just made
what I think to be
the biggest move of this season.
So I want
to paint that target on him
so that
there is no target on me.
So, what's going down?
- So...
- I mean,
I'm gonna be straight.
- Like...
- Tell me.
So, I think if we want
to improve our odds
of making it to final four,
we take out Cass.
Just got to figure out
what's gonna be best
for my game.
And who's most likely
to win a challenge?
Not me, at this point.
- Cass and Owen are winning.
- I know.
And they just got refueled.
They want to vote
for Cassidy, but,
right now, I think
I want to be sitting next
to Cassidy and Owen
at the final three.
I think I've got
a better story to tell
than either of those two.
- Absolutely.
- Hey. Oh!
- Oh!
So my goal is to
take out Karla and Jesse.
If that happens, then I think
I've got a really good shot
at the million dollars.
I think that's
the smartest way to go.
the only way to go.
He does have a perfect record,
and he hasn't been
voted against.
And, uh, he's been
on the right side, I think,
- of every vote post-merge.
- Yeah.
Right now, I need to have
one-on-one times with Owen
and Cassidy and, uh,
Gabler to show them
how big of a threat Jesse is.
And if they don't see it,
they're dumb as hell.
- No one's ever voted for him.
- Okay.
- He just stole Cody's idol
and flushed two idols.
- Mm-hmm.
- Um...
- That was a historic move.
- He had...
- And that was all his idea.
I already have considered
possibly voting for Jesse.
I'm not stupid.
I fully acknowledge Jesse is
a huge threat in his own right.
But Karla...
She can talk.
- You make some
good points, Karla.
- Yeah.
And she is putting forth
a very solid argument
that Jesse needs to go.
And she's not wrong.
I mean, if he makes it
to the end, he wins.
Yes.
Decisions like this are critical
at this stage
of the game because
this vote sets the table
for the final immunity challenge
and the final Tribal Council,
and I didn't come all this way,
I didn't come back from being
left out of those early votes
just to be
a zero-vote finalist.
So I need to think long and hard
about what's best for my game.
Where do you think
you stand in a
Gabler, Owen, Jesse, you?
I think that I have
a pretty good shot
- of getting
to the final three with them.
- Okay.
But you have Jesse,
who just played the most massive
move in all of the season.
- Do you not see that?
And then, but then...
- I do.
But he's not gonna say,
"Thank you, Cassidy,
"thank you, Gabler,
thank you, Owen,
for helping me make this move."
- I'm not an idiot, Karla.
- Okay, well, that's what I...
- You don't need
to look out for me.
- Yeah? I mean...
You don't need to, like,
make me aware of these things.
- I understand the game.
- Okay. So, then, I'm...
I'm trying to figure out how
you're gonna use that
to your advantage.
Karla was definitely trying
to stir up a lot of chaos,
'cause at first,
she starts trying
to kind of pitch Jesse
and how he played
a way better game than me.
And when she starts realizing
that's not really gonna work,
she starts trying all
these different tactics, like,
basically throwing anything
at the wall
to see what will stick.
Any of the Coco votes,
anything pre-merge,
I don't know if you will be able
to use as gameplay
because it was all me and James.
So if you go home tonight,
that's what you're gonna
- go tell the jury?
That it was all...
- Of course.
- Because I'll be on the jury.
- Yeah.
And my vote is not
gonna go to you.
Karla tried to pull this, like,
whole scare tactic on me
where she's gonna come after me
and smear my name
to the jury, and I...
You know, I just kind of
lost a lot of respect for her
for pulling that move on me
when we've played
so long together.
I think she's upset that I maybe
have gotten the better of her
and that I've formed
better social relationships
and outwitted her
to the point where I'm gonna
be the one in the final four
and potentially not her.
And so I'm worried
about what she might do tonight.
She's literally been throwing
your name out all day...
I'm frustrated that Karla is
trying to paint a target on me
because, like,
the plan was to vote for Cass.
I mean, she's pretty convinced
that she's going home.
She said, it's either me
or her, so...
I think either you or me.
I'm getting definitely
a little nervous now.
I know I shouldn't,
but you just never know
in this game.
In my heart, I feel like,
you know, I could go with
the majority and vote Karla,
but at the same time,
my head is telling me
to vote out Cassidy.
She could easily win
final immunity.
So the best strategic move
for me is to take her out.
I don't think so.
I'm at a dilemma here
because, like, aah!
This is it. Like,
there's only one more challenge,
and then there's the final four
fire-making challenge.
So, I'm really sort of
weighing out my options here.
I have this idol
that nobody really knows about
and I'm just trying
to figure out what I can do
at Tribal Council
with this idol.
I'm gonna use it. I just got
to figure out how to use it.
All right. Final five.
Last time you can vote somebody
out of this game, Jesse.
You survive tonight,
your fate is in your hands.
You either win at final four,
somebody takes you
to the final three,
or you get to make fire.
How does that shift the level
of threat management
that has to happen
if you think you're the one
that everybody's worried about?
Uh, you just start
trying to play up
everybody else's threat level.
You start trying to push them
in front of the bus.
I had, uh, you know, someone
earlier today try and push me
in front of the bus and play
at my threat level and...
You looked directly at Karla.
Yeah, Karla has, uh,
been throwing punches today, so...
Well, last Tribal, someone
stole someone's idol
and then washed another idol
and then managed
to save someone, right?
And I was like, "Dang."
That is one of the best moves
I've ever seen on Survivor.
We're talking about Jesse.
And we're talking exactly
about Jessie.
And, you know, the jury sees
the one person
who takes the idol and says
who they're playing it for.
That is the memory
that's engraved
in the jury's mind
of who made that move.
So you're saying,
"Jesse made a big move.
That's why it should be Jesse
that we take out"?
Exactly.
So, Jesse, from your standpoint,
when you hear that happening,
what do you do?
I feel good tonight.
Like, I feel good.
I mean, Owen's safe,
and I know I'm safe
because I've been hanging
onto this little thing
since Dwight went home.
And, uh, so...
I-I'm punching my ticket
to the final four tonight,
so either way...
I mean, I'm good.
You know, I'm good. I'm fine.
Cassidy, your jaw was open
- for that entire time.
- Yeah.
I think that was Jeanine's idol,
maybe, in his pocket.
So I guess
Dwight pulled a switcheroo
and maybe gave Jeanine's idol
to him.
It looks pretty familiar to me.
I mean,
that looks like the bead
that Jeanine got off
my bag back at Baka way back.
So, I-I was also under
the impression that it went home
with Dwight, so, um,
my jaw dropped
just like everyone else's.
Karla, does it
make you nervous now that
Jesse has dangled
what he says is an idol?
Owen says, "I recognize a bead,"
so that might be an indicator.
Yeah, I mean, it's...
It was a flex.
He has an idol, if it's real.
So, at this point,
if anyone wants
to make any other move, I mean,
there are two other options.
Cassidy, she's basically talking
- you or Gabler.
- Yeah. No, of course.
I could see her kind of driving
any pitch at this point.
That's how good
of a player she is,
you know, and-and that's
the reason that
she's being targeted tonight, as
much as she's trying to downplay
- her threat level.
- I don't know.
Like, honestly,
maybe it's because
I'm being honest.
Maybe it's because
they're like, "Let's just
get her to shut up
and send her to the jury."
But they think I'm a threat?
I mean, you have threats
in front of you.
If people want to make bigger
moves-- and I don't know if
you want to entertain
doing an even bigger move--
I mean, the floor
is open, right?
- Let's do it.
- Yeah, I mean, so,
I've been thinking
about this all day, you know?
I definitely will
entertain more ideas
if you have 'em, so...
Would you like to dance, sir?
- We can dance.
- Let's dance.
Um...
- Jesse, can we talk to you?
- Yeah.
- The two of you?
- Come over here?
- Yeah.
- Just the two of us.
- Okay, cool.
So, Owen, how you feeling
- right now?
- Freaking the heck out.
- Like, just thinking about...
- For real?
Yeah, for real.
I mean, we have...
This has been
a very subtle season,
and to have it finally boil over
like this is just...
it's wild.
This is a lot, Jeff.
- Okay.
- Wow.
And just like that,
everybody sat back down together.
- How are you feeling, Cassidy?
- I mean, I'm definitely
more nervous
than when I started the night.
You know, Karla's been trying
to talk up like
she's less of a threat than me
and... and yada, yada, yada.
She's been pretty much
saying that
about everybody
and everything, and...
But, you know,
I think me and Jesse also have
a really good relationship,
and we've worked together
on many votes,
and including this last vote.
And so, you know,
I mean, I hope that
that holds some sway to him.
Gabler, how about you?
You know, the-the turmoil
and the chaos that's been
going on all day today?
Everyone has been
vehemently targeted
with a great plan,
and then, like,
literally, when you turn away,
somebody else walks up.
There's another one, and
it's-it's for the next person,
the next person.
It's anybody.
And on that note,
it is time to vote. Gabler,
- you're up.
- Gotcha.
I liked you in this game,
but I would like you better
on my résumé.
If anybody has
an advantage or an idol
and you want to play it,
now would be the time to do so.
I don't think I need it,
um, but my good friend Cody
taught me to always
take the guarantee.
- So I'm playing the idol
on myself.
- Got it.
This is a hidden immunity idol.
Any votes cast for Jesse
will not count.
All right, I'll read the votes.
First vote: Jesse.
Does not count.
Karla. One vote Karla.
- Karla.
That's two votes Karla.
- Oh, yes.
Fourteenth person voted out
of Survivor 43: Karla.
That's three. That's enough.
And that's how
you play a game, you guys.
You're a rock star.
- Good game, Karla.
- Thank you.
That was amazing, man.
Oh, man!
This feels so good, Jeff.
- Karla?
- Yes.
The tribe has spoken.
- Good luck, y'all.
- Have a great night.
- I love y'all.
- Bye, Karla.
Well, you have made it
to the final four.
Tomorrow, you will compete in
your final immunity challenge.
Try to get some sleep.
Grab your torches.
Head back to camp. Good night.
Good night, Jeff.
I think I played
a kick-ass game
and to hear people think
that I was a great threat,
a great player,
that is the highest honor,
I think, in this game.
There's no other way
I would have wanted to go.
If you think you have what
it takes to live in a jungle,
compete in challenges
and vote each other out,
apply to be on Survivor.
Come on in.
Welcome to day 25...
and your final
immunity channel.
All right.
Shall we get to your final
immunity challenge?
- Yes, sir.
- Yes.
One more time.
Owen, got to take back
- the necklace.
- All right.
- Thank you.
Once again,
and for the last time,
immunity is back up for grabs.
For today's challenge,
you're gonna use a long fork
to maneuver a bowl
through a channel.
When you get to the top,
you'll place your bowl,
head back for the next one.
What makes it tricky
is the entire structure
sits on a spring, which means
if you hit the structure
too hard, it will wobble,
your bowls will drop,
you got to start again.
First person
to stack 15 bowls...
...wins immunity,
guaranteed a spot
in the final three,
where you will
get a chance to plead
your case to your jury
about why you deserve the title
of Sole Survivor
and the million dollars.
In addition,
and equally important,
you decide who sits next to you
and who you force to make fire,
and that may not be
the same decision for everybody.
All right, a lot of power,
the kind of power
that could be worth
a million dollars,
but first you got to win.
We're gonna draw for spots.
We'll get started.
Here we go.
The last time drawing for spots.
All right, here we go.
Biggest challenge
of Survivor 43 is right here.
Win this,
you are in the final three.
Survivors ready?
Go.
This is it.
Final challenge is on.
You have 15 bowls
you have to stack.
You just can't hit
that structure very hard.
Especially when
your stack gets higher.
And it should be easy at first.
Jesse dropped.
He's got to go back.
Owen drops.
Cassidy getting her first one
through with no problem.
Cassidy gets her first bowl.
There's a learning curve
to this.
Gabler places his first.
Gotcha.
Owen places his first.
Jesse taking his time. Jesse
the only player in the game
who has not won
individual immunity.
Cassidy working with her second.
She's got two. Owen has one.
Jesse working on his first.
Gabler has one.
There are 15 total.
Right now, it's early.
There's a decent breeze today,
which is going to come into play
when your stack gets higher.
It's going to wobble.
Right now, it is Gabler,
Cassidy and Owen all very close.
Jesse's a little bit behind.
Day 25, season 43,
you want to get to the end--
the final three--
this is it right here.
Gabler up top.
It is Gabler at 11,
Cassidy at ten,
Owen at ten,
Jesse working on his eighth.
This is where it gets tricky.
Can you withstand the wind?
That is what
this is gonna come down to.
Here comes the wind. A big gust.
Cassidy taking a lot of time,
wanting to make sure
it is centered.
Cassidy has 11.
Owen placing his eleventh.
He's in it.
We got a challenge right now.
Lot of people in it.
Gabler with a one-bowl lead.
He's at 12.
Cassidy and Owen are at 11.
Here comes another gust of wind.
That stack is moving.
- Damn!
- Gabler--
he loses most of his stack.
Get out of there.
Get 'em all back.
Gabler's got
to get everything back.
He's now down to three.
- Oh, boy.
- It is now Cassidy in the lead.
If she can get this to stick,
it'll be number 12.
Owen with his 12th.
They both have it
at the same time.
Three bowls left
for Cassidy and Owen.
Jesse with nine.
It would be Owen's
fourth individual immunity win.
It would be Cassidy's third.
That's what you needed
is a break.
And the break came
when Gabler dropped.
That wind played a part.
And the stack was not straight.
We are tied at 12.
Cassidy and Owen both working
on their 13th.
You can see how high it is.
You've got to reach now.
Owen has his 13th!
He's in the lead.
Cassidy has 13,
right behind him.
Here we go. Two bowls left.
It is Cassidy and Owen
for a guaranteed spot
in the final three.
Owen drops!
He's got to go back.
That opens the door for Cassidy.
It is now Cassidy in the lead.
Not by a lot,
just a few seconds.
Cassidy halfway up the channel.
Owen right on her tail.
Cassidy has a time advantage,
but it's very difficult.
The wind is moving her stack
right now.
As she places her 14th.
Cassidy is down
to one bowl left.
Here goes Owen,
trying to stay in this.
Owen drops and loses everything!
This is it right here
for the win.
Cassidy has a lot of time.
The only thing
that can hurt Cassidy right now
is either Cassidy
or a big gust of wind.
This is when you want
to be as steady as possible,
which is very tough.
25 days into Survivor,
and here comes the wind...
...moving that stack.
Owen taking his time.
Slowed down.
He knows it could be over
right here.
Cassidy placing her 15th
and final bowl.
She's got to get it to stick
and get back to her platform.
That is going to do it.
Cassidy wins
individual immunity!
Her third of the season!
And guaranteed a spot
in the final three.
And it lasted just long enough
before the wind toppled it.
- A huge win on day 25.
- Good job.
Cassidy will be
in the final three.
Cassidy will have
a lot of power,
deciding who sits next to her
and who she forces to make fire.
Wow. What an effort.
All right, Cassidy,
come on over.
Once again, for the third time,
- individual immunity is yours.
- I can't believe it.
This one is as big as it gets.
You have done
what you dream about,
which is put yourself
in a position
where you can plead your case
to the jury,
- and you have enormous power.
- Yeah.
- What is the fear?
- Yeah, I mean,
it's beyond description.
Um, for me, like, I looked up
to so many amazing women
that played this game, and now
I'm just thinking, like,
I might be that person
who's inspiring
other little girls to come out
and live out their dream.
And, like, you can be a badass.
You can... you can do it,
and I...
I mean, this could be a
million-dollar necklace for me.
I'm just really grateful to have
the power that I do tonight.
Now you have two big decisions.
Who do you put next to you--
which is probably somebody
you believe you can beat--
and who do you force
to make fire, which, in theory,
would be somebody you're
uncertain if you can beat.
One thing we know for sure--
you're not gonna be voted out.
You want to be
at the final three.
- You're in the final three. Congratulations.
- Hell yeah.
- Thank you so much.
- Great job, Cass.
As for the rest of you,
busy afternoon.
I'm sure there's gonna be
a lot of politicking going on.
I'll give you time
to get to it.
Grab your stuff.
Head back to camp.
- Thank you.
- See you tonight
at Tribal Council.
This was the biggest win
of the season for me.
It comes with
a really heavy decision.
You have to consider,
who do I want
to have to make fire?
And Jesse, just based
on his performances
at the last two
Tribal Councils, I really
don't feel comfortable
sitting next to Jesse right now.
So my big question is
who do I think has a better shot
of beating Jesse
in this fire-making challenge?
I won the final immunity
challenge! Oh, my God.
I knew how crucial
this win was for me.
I mean, being able
to have this power
in the game
and not leave my fate to one
of my fellow tribemates
right now...
- So close.
- I know.
That also gives me the power
to make a decision tonight
about who I want
to see face off in fire.
And so, I mean, this win could
not have come at a better time.
Oh. Oh, God.
- Nice work.
- Oh.
- Nice. Hi.
- Nice work.
- Nice work. What's that?
- Oh, that's our...
- Practice.
- Wow.
I spent the whole
walk back from the challenge
thinking about what's best
for my game,
and it was conflicting,
'cause what would be best
for my chances
of winning would be
to go head-to-head
against Jesse.
I think, to the jury,
Jesse is the top dog.
He is the biggest threat to win,
and he will be
making a fire tonight.
So if I were to go
to fire and win,
that would be my best chance
of getting votes
at final Tribal.
But losing today
in such close fashion--
it's just defeating
to get knocked down once again.
You know, you take enough hits
in a day or in 25 days.
Like, you reach a point
where you're just tired.
And part of me almost just said,
"I'm ready to give up."
But that's not what I want
to take away from this game,
and that's not...
that's not what
all this has been about.
One of life's great lessons is
what do you do
when you fall down?
You get back up.
And today,
I fell.
And I kind of laid there
for a while, and...
...that's not... that's not me.
That's really not me.
That's not who I am as a person.
I'm not a quitter.
I'm gonna give Cassidy a crack,
see if I can
get myself into fire
and take out Jesse
in the fire-making challenge.
I firmly believe that
- if you put me in
against Jesse...
- Mm-hmm.
- I win.
- Yeah.
Like, I genuinely believe that.
So you just need to figure out
if you think Gabler
or I has a better chance of...
Yeah. I just... I need
- whoever goes
against Jesse to win.
- To win.
It sucks.
I haven't won a single
immunity challenge.
I still was hoping
to at least win one so
my kids could see that,
but I didn't.
I lost the most important one today,
which is, uh, the one
where you get to decide,
you know, who sits next to you
in the final three
and who has to go to fire.
If I was in that position
and there was somebody
who had played, like, my game,
especially with the last two
Tribal Councils, being so flashy
with the moves or whatever,
I'd throw them in fire
right away, so,
I'm going to fire.
This is all that matters.
I'm 100% locked in
on this fire-making challenge.
This is, like, my one shot.
If I'm gonna make fire,
I want to make it
against Cassidy because I think
that's my best shot at winning.
I think that...
I think that you should
make fire against me.
- Okay.
- Because
if I'm the biggest threat
in the game at this point,
you could eliminate any doubts
- by beating me in fire... and...
- Yeah. I mean, I don't know.
I don't know how much weight
people actually hold
in the fire-making,
but it's a fair point.
Jesse knows that I'm probably
the worst at fire, and he thinks
he can beat me more than he can
beat Gabler and Owen
and he's scared of that, and so
he's trying to convince me
that the only way
that I'm gonna win the game
is to go up next to him, but
no way in hell am I giving up
this necklace. I earned it.
I'm, like, one...
I'm one challenge away.
There's one thing
standing in my way right now...
...between me
and a million dollars,
between me
and, like, being able...
...between me and being able
to give my kids,
like, that security...
...that I never had, so...
...I'm not gonna stop.
You want to talk?
Yeah, sure.
So what are you thinking?
It's your show.
Do you think
you could beat Jesse in fire?
- Yeah. Mm-hmm.
- You really do?
Can I see you make fire?
- Sure.
- Like, you know, like,
- watch you practice?
- Sure.
I've been playing this game
out of the spotlight,
so I think I need
a very public, big move.
And I want more than anything
to go make fire
to win even more credibility
with the jury.
- Now, fire's gonna go right in
there when I do it, all right?
- Yup.
But I'm running on pure heart
with not a lot of food.
Might just want
to start scraping a little more
- magnesium.
- Yeah.
I am so hungry. I've lost
probably 20, 25 pounds.
Every time I stand up or move
too fast, I get lightheaded.
My muscles burn all the time.
But I got to
pull it together tonight.
I got to do this.
I need Cassidy
to put me in for fire.
Nice.
I'm playing for bigger things.
People need me
and people are counting on me.
I'm gonna do something
that's never been done
in Survivor history.
I'm gonna donate
the entire prize to charity.
Yeah.
Winning this game is about
winning a million dollars
and being able
to donate 100% of that prize
to a patient population
that I hold dear--
Veterans in need--
so I have to win.
I'm gonna get it.
Let me get it here.
I am trying to weigh,
between Owen and Gabler,
who do I think
has a better shot,
not only of beating Jesse,
but who do I think can beat him
that also won't come back
with that boost
on the résumé that
they needed to beat me.
I think that Owen
has a potential
to beat Jesse
in fire-making, but
if I put him in fire,
and he comes back
in this blaze of glory, like,
that might be the ammunition
that he needs
to steal the win from me.
I'm nervous about Gabler
because he's been seeming
a little bit weak,
a little feeble.
That makes me a little nervous
putting him up to Jesse.
But I think that
if he did beat Jesse
that wouldn't be enough for him
to take the win from me.
I think I would still
beat him in the end.
So that's why
it would be a better choice
to put Gabler up there.
But can Gabler
actually beat Jesse?
That's the question.
Is he strong enough?
I'm playing for
people out there
that are counting on me,
and tonight
I'm gonna have to do
something spectacular
to win this game.
I fought so hard
to make it this far,
and I still have a chance.
I need Cassidy to put me in fire
and win, and triumphantly
go to the final three.
If I pull this off,
I think I win the game.
I just think about my kids,
I just think about my wife.
A lot riding on it.
This decision,
if I make it right,
will change my entire life.
But I won't know
if it's the right decision
until the jury votes
are read for the winner.
All right. First question.
Cassidy, what's that feel like
to walk in knowing
all the jury is looking
for who has the necklace?
Yeah, I mean,
it's a pretty good feeling.
You know, this was the paramount
win of the season. I think
this is the most monumental time
to have this
around your neck,
and to be the last person
to win this necklace
and for it to be my third win,
I mean, I'm super proud, and
I'm proud to wear it tonight.
And I feel like I earned
this spot in the final three.
And that's-that's huge,
so, I feel great.
You have earned it.
You have three
individual immunity wins.
There were nine
individual immunity necklaces.
You won a third of them,
Owen won another third.
- It's a dominating performance.
- Thank you.
With your win today,
you have a spot
in the final three where you get
to plead your case,
your story to your jury
about why you played
the best game, you deserve
the title of Sole Survivor
and the million dollars.
- But equally important...
- Yup.
...is the decision
you're about to make, which is,
who are you gonna take with you
and put in that second spot
and who are you going
to force to make fire?
So, before we get to that,
let's just talk about the day.
Because you go back, and now
you're the center of attention.
- Yeah.
- I'm assuming
everybody is pitching their way
around you.
You know, of course,
everyone kind of lined up
to talk to me
and pitch and plead their case.
And so, I mean,
this is definitely a burden
I was carrying today. As happy
as I am to have the burden,
this could make or break my game
depending on what I do tonight.
Jesse, you made a pitch.
What was it?
Uh...
I had a hard sell.
So my pitch to her was,
if you want to sort of,
like, guarantee a win,
if I'm that big of a threat,
then, like,
you should sit
and make fire with me.
Cassidy, how was that received?
Uh, you know, to me, I think
that that is the kind of move
that somebody would make
if they feel like
they haven't really earned
their spot in the final three.
But for me, I trust in a game
that I've played.
I've played a strong game
through and through
in every aspect.
So for me to, like, risk that,
basically, is in
his best interest, not mine,
because he probably thinks
that he has the best chance
of beating me at fire.
Okay, so it sounds like
Jesse's making fire,
and then it comes down
to the question of
is he gonna make it
against Gabler or Owen?
Gabler, what was your pitch?
Please let me make fire.
- I want to do it.
I want to-- If I get to
- You want to?
the final three,
I want to go into
the final three
in a blaze of glory.
That was literally what I said.
Then I worked on some coconuts,
and I'm ready
to rock it out
at one of these stations.
Wow.
Owen, what was your pitch?
Did you want to make fire?
I would love to make fire, 100%.
I would love to. I would--
I would rather go out swinging.
So, of course, I would love
that opportunity
to seize this moment.
It's really interesting
to me, Cassidy,
because you basically have
three people
are saying they want to make fire
when one of them could say,
"Hey, I'm good
- just sliding into
that second seat."
- Yeah. But to me,
this decision is not based off
of anything that they said.
It's based off
what's best for my game,
what makes the most sense
for me tonight.
So you have a very clear
point of view, and it's based on
what you think
is the best move for you,
which is the only thing
- you care about right now.
- Yeah.
Who are the other two people
sitting next to you
and how do you convince
this group that you played
the best game of the three?
So, are you ready
to tell us your decision?
Yeah, I think I am.
Let's start with
who are you going to take
and sit next to you
in that final-two spot?
Tonight I am going to...
take Owen to sit next to me.
So, Owen, you are
in the final three.
- Great.
- You will have
a shot tomorrow
to plead your case
to the jury about
why your game is better
than the woman who just
brought you there: Cassidy.
The only thing left to decide
is fire-making now
between Jesse and Gabler.
Anything either of you
want to say
before you head over
to your fire-making stations?
- How are you feeling
right now, Gabler?
- I'm feeling good.
I'm feeling good. You know,
I believe I can do this,
and I want to end my 25 days
with an exclamation mark,
and I can't think
of a better way to do it
than at one of
these stations tonight.
- Jesse, how you feeling?
- You know,
I've spent every
single minute since we got back
from the challenge
up in the forest, making fire.
The only time they saw me today
was when I was
collecting sticks.
So I'm just gonna
do what I can, give it my all.
That's the best I can do.
Gabler, Jessie,
you can both take a spot
at your fire-making station.
Good luck.
All right.
This is the only thing
you have to think about
right now in your life,
is making what could be
a million-dollar fire.
I'm gonna give you a minute
to focus on that,
and then we go.
All right, let's get to
our fire-making showdown.
You each have the same supplies.
Requirements for fire
are always the same.
Build a fire high enough
to burn through your rope
and pop your flag.
The first person to do that
takes the final spot.
The other person
will join the jury.
Could be a million-dollar fire.
- Are you both ready?
- Believe so.
Yes, sir.
Here we go. Begin.
This is it.
Day 25.
The fastest fire's
ever been made
was just under five minutes.
Season 38.
Jesse said
he worked on his all day.
Gabler sounds like he's had
a lifetime of making fires.
Jesse now gonna try to
get a little spark going.
He's got his flint.
Magnesium just helps it.
Gets you a little ignition
in there.
Ignite.
Both players prepping.
Gabler's the first
to get flame.
Good job, Gabler.
Jessie has flame.
Now you got to nurture it.
Both guys have flame.
Oh, my God,
oh, my God, oh, my God.
That hessian burns quickly
and it's impressive,
but it goes out just as fast.
You're gonna have to actually
build a structure.
Jesse nurturing a little flame.
Gabler has
a much bigger flame.
A lot of that is still hessian.
Gabler now adding sticks.
That's what you need to catch
to start building
a bigger fire.
Jesse's flame is out.
He's gonna have to start again.
Gabler trying to nurture his
to keep it going.
Jesse has played this
entire game slow and steady.
Never showed signs of panic.
Gabler adding more sticks.
He's got a decent fire going.
Will it burn high enough to
burn that rope is the question.
Jesse has flame again.
Gabler in the Clear lead
right now
if that fire continues to grow.
Jesse now has got
a little something going.
He's in it.
Gabler adds
a little more hessian.
Starting to burn
that rope a little bit.
Jesse now trying
to get his fire going.
He's gonna
have to build it quickly.
Gabler's is high and strong.
- No...
- Gabler's got
a high flame, fast.
Good job, Gabler.
- Thank you.
- Fire is burning hotter
and higher.
Jesse trying
to get back in this.
Trying to get a flame going
that can get him in this.
It is Gabler's to win
right now.
Come on, baby.
- Fire man!
- There it is!
Gabler makes fire.
The fastest fire
- that has ever been made
- Come here.
Give me a hug.
- in this final four challenge.
- Come on, that was good.
And that is it for Jesse.
Played a hell of a game.
Be proud of yourself.
I'm proud of you.
Proud of you, dude.
Jesse, I'm sorry.
Come here. I'm sorry.
I'm sorry.
Jesse, do you feel like sharing
what you're thinking?
Everyone's proud of you, dude.
Especially your family.
Um... thinking about
the people
I've been thinking about
this whole time.
You know?
Thinking about
my wife and my kids
and...
I've been playing as hard
as I have because of them.
For them. Like...
Part of the reason
I came out here
was to set an example
for my kids, right? To show
them, like, you know,
you give it your all, like,
you fight as hard as you can.
Just leave it all
out there, right?
And, uh...
I feel like I did that.
But the closer
we got to this, like,
point where I could
plead my case
for a million dollars, right?
And I felt like I played,
like, a great game.
It was right there, and it--
And it's hard because, like...
I've had to fight,
like, my entire life
to sort of, like,
get to where I'm at.
And I've always felt like
I've had to walk
this tightrope because I don't
have a safety net back home.
I don't.
And so...
...every day feels like
do-or-die back home.
Because one wrong move...
You're not gonna make any
wrong moves, dude. You're on
- an upward trajectory.
- Slips through...
it slips through your fingers.
Um...
looks like
I made a wrong move but,
you know, I think I set
a great example for my kids,
you know, just to play your
heart out, give it your all...
- And the only reason that
you're in this position
- Just had to get some tears out.
is because of how
amazing of a game
that you played
and how big of a threat
- that you were.
And I know that's not,
- I appreciate it, but...
like, that's not...
- I know that's not
what you want to
- Maybe I shouldn't have
- hear, but...
but I'm just saying,
- played that game...
like, it was out of respect.
Yeah, no,
I appreciate it. No, there's
- Jesse,
- no hard feelings.
- that really is
the biggest compliment
you can get, is that
she needed you out of the game
- in order to improve
her chances.
- Yeah, it makes sense.
And this is an example
of why this game
is so difficult to win.
As you say, one wrong move
- Yep.
- on Survivor
and you're out.
It's all good.
Gave it my all.
Sadly, Jesse, for you,
after 25 days, that is the case.
Need you to grab your torch.
- All right.
- All right, bro.
- Appreciate it. This was fun.
- Great game, Jesse.
- Thank y'all.
It was so much fun.
- Thank you, buddy.
- Love you, Jesse.
- I'm glad to have met you.
- It was so much fun. Yeah,
so much fun.
Gave it my all.
- Yes, you did.
- Sure did.
Jesse, the tribe has spoken.
♪ ♪
Come on.
Time for you to go.
- Ooh!
- See you, buddy.
Great game, Jesse.
All right.
You've made it
to the final three.
You each have
a different story for
how you got here,
and tomorrow night you will be
defending those stories
as the power shifts
to this side of Tribal Council.
Eight people that
you had a hand in voting out
are now in charge.
They're going to interrogate you
tomorrow and make you prove
why you deserve
the title of Sole Survivor
and the million dollars
that goes with it.
You have one more night in Fiji.
Try to get some sleep.
I have a feeling
you are going to need it.
Grab your torches,
head back to camp.
- Thank you, Jeff.
- Good night. Good night, Jeff.
- Thanks, Jeff.
I was playing to set an example,
just plain and simple,
you know, for my family,
but also for, you know, the kids
who are in juvenile hall
right now. You know, I want
everybody to know that,
you know, just
give it your all and just
go after life and chase your
dreams and just fight for it.
And, you know, sometimes you're
gonna come up short,
but at the end of the day,
you're still gonna be a winner.
Coming up, the winner
of Survivor 43...
Oh, my God.
...the Survivor aftershow
and your first look
at Survivor 44.
This is it, brother.
We made it through last night.
- We did.
- The only three people
- that went this far.
- Mm-hmm.
It's amazing
to wake up here knowing that
I can't be voted out.
Jeff is not gonna
snuff my torch.
To make the final three
is beyond comprehension.
Yeah. This is the most important
presentation of my life.
The key, I think, is to figure
out what they're looking for.
But there is still
a monkey on my back
knowing that the battle
is yet to come.
There is this daunting
grim reaper lurking,
knowing that I have to
go in front of the jury.
I know some of them are bitter.
I don't care.
I've been the underdog
for the majority of this game.
Tonight is no different.
This is a million-dollar
Tribal Council,
and I'm gonna give it
everything I have.
Owen embodies
what it means to never give up,
because you never know
where you might end up.
Owen made it to the end
without being on the right
side of the votes.
That is his case
that he has to plead.
He has to come out
with some fire.
I am rooting for Owen.
I'd rather vote for the underdog
than the person that
was just sitting pretty
on the majority
this entire game.
- Great job, everybody.
- Oh!
- Yay.
- Final three breakfast!
- Oh...
- Oh, my God.
- Wow.
This feast is huge because
when you're so depleted,
it brings your body
and your mind
back into the game.
- We did it. Cheers.
- Cheers.
- Final three.
- Cheers. Final three.
Congratulations, everybody.
At 51 years old, I made
final three.
I didn't get drug along.
I made fire. I've got--
I've suffered, I've battled.
And I've never received
one vote.
Which is why, tonight, I hope
I get all of their votes
on parchment.
Gabler played a good game.
Some people look at it,
"Oh, he's flipping
and he's flopping,
he's back and forth,"
but he did that
to further his game.
Gabler is just such an enigma.
I really just need him
to explain what parts
were intentional
and what parts were not.
He's a 51-year-old man,
20 years older
than everybody else.
So for him to be able
to integrate
with a much younger cast--
that's impressive.
So, I want him
to hinge his game
on the relationships he built,
because that
is where Gabler thrives.
Wow.
Now, you guys have all
watched the show
- for a long time, right?
- Mm-hmm.
How long you dreamed about
playing?
Can you imagine making it
to the final three?
- I cannot.
- And then starving for so long,
having this
delicious breakfast and, like,
having a one-third shot
- at a million dollars
and the title?
- Crazy.
This is the best day of my life.
It's been a long journey
and I am so
proud of myself and everything
that I've accomplished.
I feel like
I came out as a dark horse
in this competition.
You know?
Nobody really saw me coming.
I was never once
on the wrong side of the votes,
all the while
winning immunity challenges.
I have the social and the
strategic and the physical game
to back up, you know,
why I deserve to win.
Cassidy-- she didn't
rock the boat.
She was able to align herself
with big threats.
By the time people realized
she was a community threat,
it was too late. They needed
her votes to move forward.
I tried to get Cassidy out
multiple times,
but she got me out.
I saw the danger in
the sweet girl,
and nobody else really did.
Cassidy should have
gone up against me
at fire, but if she's
able to show that
she survived being targeted
and was always voting correctly,
she could win my vote.
I'm just curious, like
what they're thinking going in.
It's like,
who's the front-runner?
Who needs to impress us?
- Yeah.
- Either way,
I gave it everything I had...
- Same.
- and I'll be proud
of the outcome.
Mm-hmm.
I had to fight harder
than anyone else in this game
to stay alive,
and I'm gonna defend my journey
with everything I have.
Definitely the biggest
night of my life,
and hopefully
the best night of my life.
I'm on the one-yard line
for a million dollars.
Failure's not an option
at this point.
Owen-- he's the underdog.
You're the champion.
I'm the outsider.
I want to see fireworks
at final Tribal. I want them
to show me that they earned
that million dollars.
Who I vote for will be decided
at Tribal Council.
I want everyone
to fight for their lives.
You have to stand
behind your moves.
Plead your case.
Games are gonna be fact-checked.
Like, show me your résumé
and your references.
If people can explain
unseen moves that they made,
you have my vote.
If you play
an amazing game and then
shoot yourself in the foot
at the end,
you could lose
a million dollars.
I'm hoping there's
some punches
thrown at each other
because, ultimately,
they're gonna have to snap
some necks to cash that check.
Come fierce and come correct
and let the jury know
you played better than us
and that's why you're sitting
right there. Whoever does that,
for me, gets my vote.
Welcome to your final
Tribal Council.
Congratulations on doing
what 15 other players
couldn't do:
get to the end.
You survived that
early tribe stage,
you transitioned into
the individual stage,
you started building your jury.
You got through that final push
where you had to start over.
Now you're at the last stage.
This is claim your victory.
If Survivor is a mountain,
this is you at the top
with your flag saying,
"This is my victory."
And if you don't
defend your game,
this jury will
flick you off that mountain,
send you tumbling down.
That's their job.
Tonight, the power in the game
shifts right there.
Eight people you had a hand
in voting out
will now determine your fate.
Your job
is to examine their game
by asking questions,
holding them accountable.
With respect,
they did kick your ass.
You're trying to determine
who you think's
deserving of your vote
for a million dollars.
I'm gonna give you a moment
to think of your questions,
to prepare for their questions,
and then we'll get started.
Okay, let's get into
our final Tribal Council.
We'll look at the game
in three big areas--
the social, the physical
and the strategic--
knowing that they all overlap.
And ultimately,
it is one big game.
But just so we have
some context,
- Jesse, get us started.
- Yeah.
Um...
Uh, I just want to say
all three of you should
be proud of the games
- that you played. Honestly.
- Yes, sir.
- Thank you.
- Like, you guys
did amazing. But, like,
- Thank you, Jesse.
this is not
the end of the game.
You have to earn our votes
- Yep.
- because this jury
has questions,
and they're gonna be tough
questions. And, as somebody
who went out in fire last night,
I was able to smell
the million dollars
right up until
I smelled the smoke
of Gabler's blazing fire.
So, you know, I know
how much pressure
you must be feeling
right now, and so
I want to see you go out
in a blaze of glory.
With that said, you guys
did amazing, and good luck.
- Thank you.
- Thank you, my man.
So, I would like to start off
with the first question.
How would you differentiate
your game from the others?
- And we could start with Gabler.
- You know-- Thank you, Noelle.
So, my game has been
very much relationship-based
and trust-based, being somebody
that can be counted on.
That's how I was playing.
And I'll tell you,
I've been in an alliance
with each and every
one of you guys at one point.
I was with the Coco crew.
I was with the Baka boys.
And then, raise your hand
if you were in
the Ride or Die alliance.
But I was never seen,
because I was talking
behind the scenes with
all the different alliances,
and I had multiple ways
to get deeper into the game.
Even when I was at ten,
I had a couple
of ways to get to seven.
When I was at seven, I had
a couple of ways to get to five.
When I got to five,
I had two ways to get to three.
So, by being in these different
groups, it was very helpful.
And guess what?
26 days.
No one has
written my name down,
- Mm.
- not once.
I do want you
to write my name tonight.
And I'm gonna
tell you more reasons why later,
but for now,
I hope that answered
your question.
Thank you.
- Cassidy.
- Yeah. So,
for me, I feel like
I've always had
my fingers on the pulse
of this game.
I always knew where
the votes were going.
Every vote that I cast,
it was the right vote.
Not one surprise or blindside
the entire game. And I think
the only other person
in this season who maybe
could say that is Jesse.
But he's on the jury and I was
able to make it to the end here.
And I also had
really close bonds
with Karla and with James
on the Coco tribe,
which saved me through
those first couple votes.
And then, I knew
if I went to the end
with some of these people,
that they were gonna beat me.
So I had to form bonds
with, you know, with Gabler
and with Owen, who were left out
of a lot of the votes,
who were on the bottom.
And then also, I know
that this is not personal,
and this was
nobody's intention, but
there was an historical number
of women voted out at pre-merge.
Like, to be
the last woman standing,
I think,
is also a feat in itself.
And-and that's something
that I'll claim as well.
- Owen.
- Yes, sir.
Well, y'all,
my Survivor story has been
one of the underdog.
I am a superfan,
I am a student of the game,
and I came out here thinking
I would play a brilliant game,
and that all came crashing down,
basically, in 24 hours.
On Baka, we were a disaster
from the beginning.
I got my name written down
on night three,
and I legitimately thought
I was gonna be the first boot,
and that my dream was gonna
come crumbling down.
We get to the merge, and things
just get even worse from there.
I end up on the wrong side
of the Elie vote, and so,
I had to claw and scratch
and dig myself out of a hole
much deeper than either
of these folks were in.
And so, I saw one clear path,
and that was
to sit with these two,
working with Jesse, to then
take the power position
with some options.
Was I perfect out here?
Abso-fruit-ly not.
No way, no how.
But I learned that
I don't need to be perfect.
I just need to be me.
So if you respect an underdog,
if you respect determination,
hard work,
I think you should consider
giving me your vote tonight.
And I think that's how
I differentiate myself.
Thank you, guys.
James.
Man, um,
I respect all three of you.
Really good job.
Um, with that being said, Owen,
trust-wise, when did you
stick your neck on the line
for an ally to try to get them
to stay in this game?
I would say
when you trusted me to
steal your vote to get him out.
Yes, that was a big one.
That's when I knew I wanted
to trust you and work with you.
Yeah, that was a big day.
And since you brought it up,
Noelle, I'll mention that.
So, I viewed James and Karla
as the biggest threats
in the game,
and I saw this
golden opportunity for us
to lull them into
a false sense of security
that I am going home.
Noelle will steal my vote,
and then they will not
play an idol,
they will not play a Shot in
the Dark, and we are good to go.
And I had to trust in Noelle
to pull that off
without bamboozling me.
The Gabes.
So, the Elie vote-- let's talk
about that for a second.
Elie had looked through my bag.
Also, it was Elie, but...
Yes, go ahead.
Yeah. I-I... This is...
I'd... I'm... It's my time
to come clean, Gabler.
- Yes, ma'am.
- Your instincts are spot on.
And I have to say, I'm so sorry.
I did go through your bag.
And you have killer instincts.
- You're a rock star. No worries.
- I just have to tell you that
'cause that's been
eating away at me, and I just...
- I really needed to finally
be honest with you.
- No problem.
- No problem. I totally get it.
I totally get it.
- All love.
So, I was... I was like, "Okay,
something's not right here."
And I stirred that pot.
Me and Elie even had
a very public argument in camp,
and we voted her out,
and then she flamed me in front
of the whole jury here.
Like, "That's what you get
for trusting Gabler."
And I was like,
"I am way too high-profile here.
"Like an alligator,
I need to go underwater
and start playing
a different game."
- Thank you.
- Okay.
So, Cassidy, can you give me
one specific move
that you did pre-merge
to help propel you
into the merge?
Yeah. Um, I think
the most important move
was building my relationship
with you and with James.
I trusted y'all
whenever the vote switched
last-minute off of Geo
onto Lindsay, and then,
through our relationship,
we were able to blindside Geo
and take control of-of kind of
the tribe in that way.
And so, that was the vote that
I made that helped propel me
and, you know,
our alliance into the merge.
Thank you.
- Jesse.
- Yeah, so,
I run surveys for a living,
which is all about extracting
information from people.
Give me an example of when you
used your social relationships
to get information
in this game
and how you used that
to get ahead.
So after the Elie takeout,
Alli-Gabler had
to go underwater...
- Alli-Gabler.
- and-and hang out
by the water's edge
because you don't
just say,
"Oh, it's me. I'm the guy." No.
Even though it could have been
Gabler in the library
with a coconut,
I wanted it to be
a total secret, right?
So, because of my social game
and the information
I was getting, I was able
to get deeper in the game
with more options.
So, for me, I, like you,
had all of the right information
that I needed at every Tribal.
I mean, I was in the trenches
in all of those votes.
I was talking to everybody.
I was making sure
that the plan that I was in on
was the right plan
for every single vote.
You know, also,
I had a mental checklist of all
the people who had gunned for me
in this game. Ryan was trying
to blindside me.
And then, Noelle, I found out
you wrote my name down
at the merge.
You know, no hard feelings, but
same with Sami. He tried
to come after me at one point.
Cody threw my name out there
at one time, Karla as well.
So all of these people,
I knew, if they were
gunning for me once,
they're probably gonna
try to get me out again.
And I have to get them out
of this game
before they can get me.
I feel like I have
a great understanding
of Cass' core alliance
at this point,
but I'm really curious
as to, Gabler and Owen,
who you feel like
your closest allies were
and how you worked
with them post-merge.
Sure. Um, Noelle and I had gone
on that journey together
on day seven.
It-it sounds corny, but
when I-I looked her in the eye
on that hike, I felt like we-we
kind of just got each other,
and I felt like
you were someone I could trust.
Eventually,
once Noelle was blindsided,
I decided to make my bed
with these two, plus Jesse
and go to the final four
with them.
- Gabler?
- My core alliance.
You know, honestly, I... Honestly,
I had a few of them.
I was in Ride or Die,
I was in with Sami
and I was in with Owen.
Although me and you went
in and out for a while,
and then we came together
post-merge,
and we were locked
the rest of the way.
Um, also, you know, I was in
with Ryan, Noelle, so...
- I-I got a question
for you, Gabler.
- Yes, sir.
You had decided to flip
and go with Jesse and Cody.
Was your intention
to go with these guys
for the rest of the way
or were you actually continuing
to kind of go back and forth?
I think that's something
that we would like to know.
I was in Ride or Die
to ride or die.
And, you know, that's having
trust and not being targeted.
I mean, just to think
back to day one,
to get all the way to here
and not get a vote? I mean,
- I... It's lucky, but it's a...
- That's very impressive.
Do you wonder
if part of the reason
that you didn't get any votes is
'cause people didn't
perceive you as a threat
or because, just because
you played it so well
with all of your
different alliances?
I think it was both, because
if I stayed up top,
it wasn't gonna last.
I mean, I think
you did an amazing job
of keeping me comfortable,
and that's why
I never wanted
to put your name out, so...
- Thank you.
- Yeah. You've come
to me and said,
like, "We're sort of playing
the silent, like, killers.
"You know, like, we're sort of,
like, laying low,
and we're taking people out."
And you were doing that,
so, like, if people weren't
perceiving you as a threat,
that was your intention.
Thank you.
That was the game. Thank you.
How about the physical part
of the game?
Yeah. Um, so, a majority
of the immunities
that were won were won
by these three people
right here.
A third of the immunities,
a third of the immunities,
and a ninth of the immunities.
Only two weren't won
by you guys.
At what point in the game
did you feel like you needed
to manage
your physical threat level?
Like Gabler said,
Alli-Gabler had to go down
'cause if you're
too much of a threat,
you're getting kicked out.
Yeah. I mean, I think,
for me, I honestly
didn't see myself becoming
a physical threat in this game
until, I, you know,
I won my first immunity.
And that gave me the boost
I needed to be able
to win more immunities,
and I think the most important
win that I had
was that final win,
was that power to, you know,
decide who I wanted to take out,
- the biggest threat
in the entire game.
- I have a question.
- Yeah.
- Um, I left out a little bit
about my occupation.
I am actually a Paralympian.
I run track and field
for Team USA.
- Wow.
- So, Cassidy,
I have to give it to you
for winning three
individual immunity challenges.
That is something
that you're gonna
take with you
for the rest of your life.
It's a beautiful thing,
especially being a woman.
Thank you.
I really appreciate that.
And now, with that being said,
you just mentioned
the fire-making challenge.
I would like to be walked
through your decision-making
on why you chose Gabler
to make arguably
one of the biggest moves
in taking out one of the biggest
strategic players
in this game,
and why you didn't want
to take that challenge on yourself.
Yeah. Honestly, the game
that I had played up
to that point was a good game.
You know, I didn't make
any big mistakes in this game.
You know, everything
that I did, I was always
on the right side of the votes.
I was always in the
major alliance, and I worked
my ass off to be sitting here,
and I won that immunity
fair and square.
When the pressure was at its
highest, I showed up for that,
and I ... defeated
that challenge,
and I deserved to be here.
But I also felt like
it was a strategic decision
in keeping Owen here
and not giving Owen the chance
to redeem himself in that way,
'cause he did have a little
bit of an underdog story.
And I felt like
if he made that fire,
that was gonna give him,
potentially, the boost
that he would need to, you know,
beat me in the end, and,
you know, also, even if Gabler
did win that fire challenge,
I didn't know
if it would be enough to,
you know, be able to beat me.
So that was also
a strategic decision,
and I felt like
he was the best at fire.
And so, that's why
I made that decision.
Perfect. Thank you.
Great answer.
- Thank you.
- Karla?
Yes. So, as you've seen,
I left it out there
physically and mentally,
and you saw me fighting till
I couldn't fight any longer.
- Yeah.
- Can you tell me a moment
where you have fought
until you couldn't any longer?
So, physically speaking,
obviously, last gasp.
We don't need to recount that.
But the-the main example for me
is the final five
immunity challenge.
So, for those of you who don't
know, we got an advantage clue,
and we had
to do a word scramble,
and it said to sprint
to find the advantage.
I get to the correct tree,
and Karla snatches it literally
when my hand is right there,
and in that second,
that was probably the angriest
I have ever been
in my entire life.
I screamed, I punched the tree,
I threw a rock into the ocean.
I blew this opportunity.
And so, I'm going in
feeling that I need to win.
And so, I ended up
winning immunity, my third one.
And it-it was so representative
of how my entire game has gone.
To just be constantly
going up and down
and having the highs
of winning, having the lows
of getting blindsided, and just
emotionally, physically,
that was the-the one for me
that really meant a lot.
To follow up on that,
how do you feel like
you handled the low points
in this game compared
to the high points in this game?
Uh, not great.
I mean, one of my only regrets
is how you and I
went at it that day,
and mostly how I came at you
and how I reacted,
and I-I lost my cool that day.
But in contrast,
I think I tried to remain humble
when I did win immunities.
I tried to not gloat
if I pulled off a blindside.
But that blow-up with you--
that is something
I'm ashamed of
and I wish hadn't happened.
So, we've heard a lot about
the great things you've done,
but I want to know
about your biggest mistake.
What did you do wrong,
and how do you own up to it?
I'm gonna go back to
when we lost
our immunity challenge,
and I basically
huddled Baka together--
right, Sami and Jeanine
and Owen-- and I was like,
"Look, I blew
the challenge tonight.
"You know, you guys
can vote for me.
I'll play my Shot in the Dark."
I mean, I...
It was clumsy.
That almost got me taken out.
In this game,
to put yourself out there
is not a good idea.
- Cassidy?
- Yeah, honestly,
Karla, and especially since
this question's coming from you,
I think the biggest mistake
I made is about
the last conversations that
we had before we voted you out.
And I feel like I could have
approached that better
'cause we had such a good
relationship this entire time.
But you were that big
of a threat in my eyes,
and I knew that, like,
if I sat up here
next to you that
you were gonna beat me.
And-and I just wish
that I had handled
our last conversation better
because I-I think
you're such an amazing person.
And I'm not just
pandering to you.
Like, I love you, I respect you,
and I just really regret the way
that our last conversation went
and leaving things like that.
- Thanks.
- Owen?
It's hard to choose
just one thing that I did wrong
since I had such a roller
coaster of a-of a ride.
But, um, in regards
to getting bamboozled
a few times, I don't regret
choosing the sides that I did
because they led me
on this journey.
And even if I don't win,
that growth and
that-that challenge to myself
in the journey I've been on
over the past 26 days--
it has been...
the adventure of a lifetime.
It's been so valuable to me
as a human being.
And I don't regret those at all,
but I do regret
a few conversations I had.
- Last question. Jesse, bring it.
- All right.
Um, so, I've been honest
with everybody.
You know, I have...
I got a PhD
about three weeks
before I got out here.
The thing I didn't really
tell everybody is
that the PhD is in
political science, which means
that I spent about six years
studying voting behavior,
studying elections,
studying campaigns.
And something
that's extremely important
in that is, like, persuasion.
And so I want to know
when you persuaded somebody
to vote the way you needed them
to vote and how you did it.
Um, okay, I'm gonna
go to the big vote,
post-merge, the first big vote,
the Elie vote.
I planted the seed
that she had looked through
somebody else's bag.
I pushed that
at our merge feast,
and I persuaded
each group to say,
"You know what?
I don't trust her.
I don't know
if you should, either."
And bam, first one out,
post-merge.
- Cassidy?
- So, I would probably
go to the Ryan vote
because it was like my neck
was very clearly on the line.
And Ryan did have
relationships with Cody,
he did have a relationship
with Gabler.
But I was able to convince them
to take Ryan out instead of me.
Yeah, so...
- Not-not to discredit you.
- Okay. Well, I was
under the impression
that I had... you know that, uh,
you guys were leaning more
towards going with Ryan,
so that's what...
You were definitely
part of that,
- but that was from Ride or Die.
- Yeah.
We came into Tribal--
me, Gabler, and Cody--
and we decided that if James
was gonna be on the jury,
we were gonna vote out Ryan.
If James wasn't on the jury,
we were gonna take out you.
- That was the start
of the Ride or Die.
Well, damn. You got me.
Owen.
Yeah, I'm-I'm not gonna lie.
I don't have one specific vote
where I was the driver
driving that vote.
I didn't have any advantages,
I didn't have idols.
I voted wrong at the beginning,
and was put
into this minority position.
So I can't pretend
that I was here wheeling
and dealing and making votes
happen and saying,
"Come on,
come with the Owen plan."
But I showed that
I had some strategic chops
and that I could be trusted
and that I could be a key part
of a lot of these votes.
I appreciate that answer, Owen,
truly do appreciate
that answer because it was
honest and it was humbling.
- Mm-hmm.
- Thank you.
- Great job, guys.
- Thank you, guys.
- Like, really good job.
- Great job, y'all.
- All right, jury, a great
final Tribal Council.
You held them accountable
when they needed it.
You lifted them up
when they deserved it,
and in the process,
you illuminated three
very different games
that all got them to the end.
The only question left now is
which game
you feel is most deserving
of the title of Sole Survivor
and the million dollars
that goes with your vote.
I'm gonna give you a minute
to take it all in
and then we will vote.